/**
 * Created by pfu on 27/05/14.
 */

if (Quizzes.find().count() === 0) {
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "Which military thinker said: “Even the finest sword plunged into salt water will eventually rust.” ", "answer_0": "Napoleon", "answer_1": "Mahan", "answer_2": "Sun Tzu ", "answer_3": "Clausewitz", "correct": "Sun Tzu "});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "Who wrote: “Strategy without tactics is the slowest route to victory. Tactics without strategy is the noise before defeat.", "answer_0": "Sun Tzu", "answer_1": "Mahan", "answer_2": "Corbett", "answer_3": "Jomini", "correct": "Sun Tzu "});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "Who stated that “the greatest victory is that which requires no battle.", "answer_0": "Clausewitz", "answer_1": "Sun Tzu", "answer_2": "Mahan", "answer_3": "Corbett", "correct": "Sun Tzu "});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "Who wrote that “War Is Merely the Continuation of Policy by Other Means.” ", "answer_0": "Corbett", "answer_1": "Clausewitz", "answer_2": "Jomini", "answer_3": "Sun Tzu", "correct": "Clausewitz"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "Which military thinker said: “War is an act of violence to compel our opponent to fulfill our will.” ", "answer_0": "Liddell Hart", "answer_1": "Corbett", "answer_2": "Eisenhower", "answer_3": "Clausewitz", "correct": "Clausewitz"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "Which military thinker coined the term ‘fog of war’. ", "answer_0": "Mahan", "answer_1": "Clausewitz", "answer_2": "Liddell Hart", "answer_3": "Douhet", "correct": "Clausewitz"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "“The hub of all power and movement...against which all our energies should be directed” is a definition of…", "answer_0": "Decisive Battle", "answer_1": "Centre of Gravity", "answer_2": "Initiative", "answer_3": "Element of Surprise", "correct": "Centre of gravity"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "What are the three elements of Von Clausewitz trinity?", "answer_0": "People, commander, government", "answer_1": "God, spirit, command", "answer_2": "Force, unity, command", "answer_3": "Commander, soldier, bravery ", "correct": "People, commander, government"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "“The general unreliability of all information presents a special problem in war: all action takes place in a kind of twilight, which...tends to make things seem grotesque and larger than they really are” is a definition of... ", "answer_0": "Post-traumatic Stress Disorder", "answer_1": "Battle fatigue", "answer_2": "The elements of seapower", "answer_3": "The fog og war", "correct": "The fog of war"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "Which military thinker said: “Everything in war is very simple, but the simplest thing is difficult. The difficulties accumulate and end by producing a kind of friction that is inconceivable unless one has experienced war.” ", "answer_0": "Mahan", "answer_1": "Corbett", "answer_2": "Clausewitz", "answer_3": "Fuller", "correct": "Clausewitz"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "What does the abbreviation SLOC stand for?", "answer_0": "Sea Lines of Communication", "answer_1": "Standard Logistical Operations Command", "answer_2": "Safety Lines of Cooperation ", "answer_3": "Safe Links of Operating and Communicating", "correct": "Sea Lines of Communication"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "Which naval strategist wrote that “it is almost impossible that a war can be decided by naval action alone.” ", "answer_0": "Gorshkov", "answer_1": "Mahan", "answer_2": "Corbett", "answer_3": "Nelson", "correct": "Corbett"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "Who claims that “Naval strategy determines the movements of the fleet whereas maritime strategy determines what part the fleet must play in relation to the action of the land forces.”", "answer_0": "Mahan", "answer_1": "Corbett", "answer_2": "Jomini", "answer_3": "Fuller", "correct": "Corbett"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "What does the abbreviation MO stand for?", "answer_0": "Military Occupation", "answer_1": "Maritime Ordenance", "answer_2": "Maritime Operations", "answer_3": "Marching Orders", "correct": "Maritime Operations"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "What does the abbreviation EW stand for?", "answer_0": "Elementary Waves", "answer_1": "Electronic Warfare", "answer_2": "Executive Warrant", "answer_3": "Extra Warning", "correct": "Electronic Warfare"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "In maritime operations what are the letters CDS short for? ", "answer_0": "Commander Supreme", "answer_1": "Capital Distance of Safety", "answer_2": "Command Deny Sea", "answer_3": "Command of the Sea", "correct": "Command of the Sea"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "This concept gives maritime forces the freedom to use the sea and to deny its use to an adversary. ", "answer_0": "Sea Denial", "answer_1": "Command of the Sea", "answer_2": "Sea Control", "answer_3": "Sea Patrol", "correct": "Command of the Sea"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "What are the letters SC short for when talking about maritime operations? ", "answer_0": "Sea Control", "answer_1": "Safety Contingent", "answer_2": "Sea Capabilities", "answer_3": "Secure Command", "correct": "Sea Control"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "This concept allows the use of the sea in specified areas for specified periods of time. ", "answer_0": "Sea Denial", "answer_1": "Area Denial", "answer_2": "Sea Control", "answer_3": "Specific Control", "correct": "Sea Control"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "What are the letters SD short for? ", "answer_0": "Secure Domain", "answer_1": "Support Deployment", "answer_2": "Safety Distance", "answer_3": "Sea Denial", "correct": "Sea Denial"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "When one party in a conflict is unable to control a maritime area but able to deny another party control of the same area, we talk about… ", "answer_0": "Sea Denial", "answer_1": "Sea Control", "answer_2": "Command of the Sea", "answer_3": "Sea Suveillance", "correct": "Sea Denial"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "What are the letters ASW short for?", "answer_0": "Anti Strike Weaponry", "answer_1": "Anti Submarine Warfare", "answer_2": "Air Support Wing", "answer_3": "Area Supprt Wing", "correct": "Anti Submarine Warfare"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "What are the letters AAW short for? ", "answer_0": "Anti Air Warfare", "answer_1": "Anti Artillery Weaponry", "answer_2": "Area Access Ways", "answer_3": "Amphibious Attack Wing", "correct": "Anti Air Warfare"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "At operational level what does the letters MCC stand for? ", "answer_0": "Maritime Cooperation Charter", "answer_1": "Military Checkpoint Centre", "answer_2": "", "answer_3": "Maritime Component Commander", "correct": "Maritime Component Commander"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "Maritime forces are said to have _________ when their mere presence results in conflict resolution with the use of force ", "answer_0": "self-sustainment", "answer_1": "poise", "answer_2": "readiness", "answer_3": "flexibility", "correct": "poise"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The ability to react immediately to almost any threat. ", "answer_0": "readiness", "answer_1": "self-sustainment", "answer_2": "flexibility", "answer_3": "poise", "correct": "readiness"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The ability of naval forces to stay in an area of operations for a long period of time. ", "answer_0": "self-sustainment", "answer_1": "flexibility", "answer_2": "readiness", "answer_3": "longevity", "correct": "self-sustainment"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "Naval forces are said to have ___________ because they can relocate over great distances quickly and at very short notice", "answer_0": "flexibility", "answer_1": "poise", "answer_2": "mobility", "answer_3": "stretch", "correct": "mobility"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The maritime environment is normally said to have ___________ dimensions", "answer_0": "1", "answer_1": "2", "answer_2": "3", "answer_3": "4", "correct": "3"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "One nautical mile equals ________ meters", "answer_0": "1,798 m", "answer_1": "1,6093 m", "answer_2": "7,532 m", "answer_3": "1,852 m", "correct": "1,852 m"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "In hydrography, the open ocean is commonly referred to as…", "answer_0": "the seven seas", "answer_1": "blue waters", "answer_2": "green ocean", "answer_3": "littorals", "correct": "blue waters"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "In hydrography, waters near coasts are normally known as…", "answer_0": "blue", "answer_1": "green/brown", "answer_2": "yellow", "answer_3": "blue/green", "correct": "green/brown waters"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "Areas from the open ocean to the shore as well as areas inland from the shore that can be supported  from sea. ", "answer_0": "blue waters", "answer_1": "littorals", "answer_2": "shorelands", "answer_3": "yellow waters", "correct": "littorals"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "To operate on the open ocean naval units must first of all have ", "answer_0": "poise", "answer_1": "initiative", "answer_2": "endurance", "answer_3": "disguise", "correct": "endurance"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The condition of readiness required for a ship to go into combat is called... ", "answer_0": "Zulu", "answer_1": "Zebra", "answer_2": "Zanzibar", "answer_3": "Zimbabwe", "correct": "Zebra"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The abbreviation PO stands for…", "answer_0": "Private Officer", "answer_1": "Premier Officer", "answer_2": "Petty Officer", "answer_3": "Post Office", "correct": "PO - Petty Officer"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The letter C in the abbreviation CPO stands for…", "answer_0": "Chief Petty Officer", "answer_1": "Commanding Petty Officer", "answer_2": "Corporal Petty Officer ", "answer_3": "Cadet Petty Officer", "correct": "CPO - Chief Petty Officer"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The letter S in the abbreviation SCPO stands for…", "answer_0": "Second", "answer_1": "Supreme", "answer_2": "Senior", "answer_3": "Sovereign", "correct": "SCPO - Senior Chief Petty Officer"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The letter M in the abbreviation MCPO stands for…", "answer_0": "Middle", "answer_1": "Master", "answer_2": "Major", "answer_3": "Mid", "correct": "MCPO - Master Chief Petty Officer"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The letters WO are short for…", "answer_0": "Warrant Officer", "answer_1": "War Officer", "answer_2": "Woman Officer", "answer_3": "Watch Officer", "correct": "WO - Warrant Officer"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The letters ENS are short for…", "answer_0": "Enlisted", "answer_1": "Entrusted", "answer_2": "Ensured", "answer_3": "Ensign", "correct": "ENS - Ensign"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The abbreviation LT stands for…", "answer_0": "Light", "answer_1": "Lieutenant", "answer_2": "Lettered", "answer_3": "Lieutenant Third", "correct": "LT - Lieutenant"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The abbrevitation LCDR is short for…", "answer_0": "Left Commander", "answer_1": "Lieutenant Commander", "answer_2": "Light Commander", "answer_3": "Liasion Commander", "correct": "Lieutenant Commander"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The letters CDR are short for…", "answer_0": "Commander", "answer_1": "Comrade", "answer_2": "Cadre", "answer_3": "Commodore", "correct": "CDR - Commander"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The abbreviation CAPT stands for…", "answer_0": "Capital", "answer_1": "Captain", "answer_2": "Capitol", "answer_3": "Capture", "correct": "CAPT - Captain"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The letters RADM are short for…", "answer_0": "Royal Administrator", "answer_1": "Rex Admiral", "answer_2": "Right Admiral", "answer_3": "Rear Admiral", "correct": "RADM - Rear Admiral"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The letters VADM refer to a…", "answer_0": "Vice Admiral", "answer_1": "Vanguard Admiral", "answer_2": "Venture Admiral", "answer_3": "Veering Admiral", "correct": "VADM - Vice Admiral"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "The abbreviation ADM is short for…", "answer_0": "Admonitor", "answer_1": "Administrator", "answer_2": "Admiral", "answer_3": "Admirer", "correct": "ADM - Admiral"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "In maritime opeartions what do the letters NMW mean?", "answer_0": "Nautical Miles Waystage", "answer_1": "Naval Maritime Warfare", "answer_2": "New Mine Warfare", "answer_3": "Naval Mine Warfare", "correct": "Naval Mine Warfare"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations", "question": "In maritime operations ASuW is short for…", "answer_0": "Abovesurface Warfare", "answer_1": "Antisurface Warfare", "answer_2": "Antisubmarine Warfare", "answer_3": "Airsurface Warfare", "correct": "Antisurface Warfare"});

    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "The part between the water and the weather deck", "answer_0": "fantail", "answer_1": "bulwark", "answer_2": "freeboard", "answer_3": "sternpost", "correct": "freeboard"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "seamanship", "question": "Where the side of the ship meets the water", "answer_0": "waterline", "answer_1": "waterboard", "answer_2": "keel", "answer_3": "freeboard", "correct": "waterline"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "seamanship", "question": "The front of a ship that extends from the keel", "answer_0": "bulwark", "answer_1": "stem", "answer_2": "forecastle", "answer_3": "freeboard", "correct": "stem"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "seamanship", "question": "The rear of a ship extending from the keel", "answer_0": "stem", "answer_1": "keel", "answer_2": "sternpost", "answer_3": "fantail", "correct": "sternpost"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "seamanship", "question": "Structural part of a ship above the main deck", "answer_0": "superstructure", "answer_1": "bridge", "answer_2": "freeboard", "answer_3": "forecastle", "correct": "superstructure"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "Timber or steel structure running along the base of a ship, supporting the framework of the whole", "answer_0": "stem", "answer_1": "sternpost", "answer_2": "hull", "answer_3": "keel", "correct": "keel"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "The sides, bottom and deck of a ship", "answer_0": "vessel", "answer_1": "bulwark", "answer_2": "hull", "answer_3": "keel", "correct": "hull"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A tall upright post, spar, or other structure on a ship, in sailing vessels generally carrying a sail or sails.", "answer_0": "boom", "answer_1": "mast", "answer_2": "antenna", "answer_3": "superstructure", "correct": "mast"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A device with two or more blades that turn quickly and cause a ship to move", "answer_0": "shaft", "answer_1": "propeller", "answer_2": "engine", "answer_3": "thruster", "correct": "propeller"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "Side of the ship above the weather deck ", "answer_0": "topside", "answer_1": "bulwark", "answer_2": "stem", "answer_3": "fence", "correct": "bulwark"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "The front part of the ship's weather deck", "answer_0": "forecastle", "answer_1": "bulwark", "answer_2": "head", "answer_3": "fantail", "correct": "forecastle"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A heavy device attached to a ship by a chain and which is thrown into the water to hold the vessel in place", "answer_0": "hoist", "answer_1": "capstan", "answer_2": "anchor", "answer_3": "windlass", "correct": "anchor"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A machine that turns so that a rope or a cable can wind around it and lift heavy weights (such as a ship's anchor)", "answer_0": "capstan", "answer_1": "roller fairlead", "answer_2": "windlass", "answer_3": "bollard", "correct": "capstan"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A post around which a rope may be tied to keep a ship/boat close to land", "answer_0": "bollard", "answer_1": "pillar", "answer_2": "capstan", "answer_3": "buoy", "correct": "bollard"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "The forward part of a ship —often used in plural", "answer_0": "forecastle(s)", "answer_1": "lead(s)", "answer_2": "bow(s)", "answer_3": "ahead(s)", "correct": "bow(s)"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A machine used on ships to let-out and heave-up heavy equipment, for example a ship's anchor", "answer_0": "capstan", "answer_1": "windlass", "answer_2": "buoy", "answer_3": "bollard", "correct": "windlass"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A special lead at the ends of a ship for use when being towed ", "answer_0": "Panama/centre lead", "answer_1": "tug lead", "answer_2": "pulling line", "answer_3": "towing rope", "correct": "Panama/centre lead"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A seaman’s term describing the ship’s bollards", "answer_0": "bolls", "answer_1": "posts", "answer_2": "bitts", "answer_3": "moors", "correct": "bitts"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "The rear end of a ship/boat", "answer_0": "bow", "answer_1": "stern", "answer_2": "fantail", "answer_3": "aft", "correct": "stern"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "The act of sending the hull of a newly built vessel from the shipyard where it was built into the water", "answer_0": "send-off", "answer_1": "launch", "answer_2": "snap", "answer_3": "lift-off", "correct": "launch"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "The breadth of a ship at its widest point", "answer_0": "breast", "answer_1": "wideout", "answer_2": "midships", "answer_3": "beam", "correct": "beam"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "If you are at a right angle to the centerline of a ship, you are... ", "answer_0": "abeam", "answer_1": "amiss", "answer_2": "ahead", "answer_3": "astern", "correct": "abeam"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A ring or block of wood with a hole in it through which rigging is passed to hold it in place or prevent it from snagging or chafing.", "answer_0": "bollard", "answer_1": "capstan", "answer_2": "fairlead", "answer_3": "windlass", "correct": "fairlead"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A vertical partition, running either fore and aft or athwartships, dividing the hull into separate compartments", "answer_0": "hold", "answer_1": "bulkhead", "answer_2": "beam", "answer_3": "divider", "correct": "bulkhead"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "If you are facing the rear of the ship, you are facing... ", "answer_0": "abeam", "answer_1": "arear", "answer_2": "aft", "answer_3": "alight", "correct": "aft"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "These allow sailors to move between decks", "answer_0": "ladders", "answer_1": "ropes", "answer_2": "rigging", "answer_3": "gangways", "correct": "ladders"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "Openings in the deck of a ship that allow sailors to move from one deck to another", "answer_0": "portals", "answer_1": "doors", "answer_2": "gates", "answer_3": "hatches", "correct": "hatches"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "The ship's toilets are commonly referred to as...", "answer_0": "lavs", "answer_1": "loos", "answer_2": "heads", "answer_3": "holes", "correct": "heads"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "The ceiling of a deck is known as the…", "answer_0": "loft", "answer_1": "head", "answer_2": "overhead", "answer_3": "roof", "correct": "overhead"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A narrow hallway connecting different areas of a ship ", "answer_0": "passageway", "answer_1": "gutter", "answer_2": "hall", "answer_3": "pathway", "correct": "passageway"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "An enclosed area on board ship, which has a specific limited function, such as for living quarters, storage, or machinery", "answer_0": "partiton", "answer_1": "apartment", "answer_2": "bulkhead", "answer_3": "compartments", "correct": "compartment"}),
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "The place from which a ship is steered", "answer_0": "superstructure", "answer_1": "helm", "answer_2": "bridge", "answer_3": "wheel house", "correct": "bridge"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "The part of the belowdecks area of a ship which is used for carrying cargo", "answer_0": "hold", "answer_1": "storage", "answer_2": "tank", "answer_3": "bulk", "correct": "hold"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A room set aside for use of the officers for social purposes and also used as their mess room", "answer_0": "restroom", "answer_1": "lounge", "answer_2": "wardroom", "answer_3": "poop", "correct": "wardroom"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A term applied to the uppermost continuous deck that is exposed to the weather", "answer_0": "long deck", "answer_1": "flight deck", "answer_2": "high deck", "answer_3": "weather deck", "correct": "weather deck"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "Structures designed for the mounting and handling of the guns of a war vessel", "answer_0": "towers", "answer_1": "turrets", "answer_2": "nests", "answer_3": "sheds", "correct": "turrets"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A vessel designed to carry aircraft and fitted with a flying deck from which aircraft are launched and on which they land", "answer_0": "", "answer_1": "", "answer_2": "", "answer_3": "", "correct": "aircraft carrier"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "Around the middle portion of a vessel as distinguished from her ends", "answer_0": "abeam", "answer_1": "astern", "answer_2": "amidships", "answer_3": "centerline", "correct": "amidships"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "Reaching across a vessel, from side to side", "answer_0": "athwartship", "answer_1": "abaft", "answer_2": "amidships", "answer_3": "acrossship", "correct": "athwartship"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "Distance from the waterline to the bottom of the ship", "answer_0": "draught", "answer_1": "abaft", "answer_2": "height", "answer_3": "breast", "correct": "draught"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A built-in berth or bed", "answer_0": "plank", "answer_1": "bunk", "answer_2": "hammock", "answer_3": "compartment", "correct": "bunk"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "The ability of something to float is equal to its…", "answer_0": "bouyancy", "answer_1": "optimism", "answer_2": "resilience", "answer_3": "updrift", "correct": "buoyancy"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A compartment offering accommodation for the crew", "answer_0": "room", "answer_1": "ward", "answer_2": "hold", "answer_3": "cabin", "correct": "cabin"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "A high speed vessel designed to keep at sea for extended periods and in which protection against gun fire is subordinated to speed and long radius of action", "answer_0": "", "answer_1": "", "answer_2": "", "answer_3": "", "correct": "cruiser"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "The space on a vessel in which the food is prepared and cooked", "answer_0": "kitchen", "answer_1": "wardroom", "answer_2": "galley", "answer_3": "cabin", "correct": "galley"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "If a ship turns upside down at sea, it…", "answer_0": "capsizes", "answer_1": "sinks", "answer_2": "rolls", "answer_3": "falters", "correct": "capsizes"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "Heavy matter such as sand, stone or water used at the bottom of a ship to improve stability", "answer_0": "tonnage", "answer_1": "ballast", "answer_2": "dead weight", "answer_3": "extra weight", "correct": "ballast"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "The skills and abilities required to efficiently and safely operate a ship.", "answer_0": "navigationseamanship", "answer_1": "", "answer_2": "engineering", "answer_3": "leadership", "correct": "seamanship"});
    Quizzes.insert({"category": "Seamanship", "question": "Distance from waterline to the highest point of the ship", "answer_0": "freeboard", "answer_1": "draught", "answer_2": "height", "answer_3": "breast", "correct": "height"});
};

if (Categories.find().count() === 0) {

    Categories.insert({"category": "Seamanship"});
    Categories.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations"});
};

if (Gamedata.find().count() === 0) {

    Gamedata.insert({"player1": "Bob L","player2": "Runa L","tilesp1":[], "tilesp2":[], scorep1:"2", scorep2:"5", questionsp1:[],questionsp2:[],
    turn:"1"});
    //Categories.insert({"category": "Maritime Operations"});

};

Meteor.startup(function () {
    // bootstrap the admin user if they exist -- You'll be replacing the id later
    if (Meteor.users.findOne("YrBYomgqmB7iymQYP"))
        Roles.addUsersToRoles("YrBYomgqmB7iymQYP", ['admin']);

    // create a couple of roles if they don't already exist (THESE ARE NOT NEEDED -- just for the demo)
    if(!Meteor.roles.findOne({name: "secret"}))
        Roles.createRole("secret");

    if(!Meteor.roles.findOne({name: "double-secret"}))
        Roles.createRole("double-secret");
});